[
  {
    "id": 1,
    "subject": "Linux",
    "question": "Which command lists files?",
    "options": ["ls", "cd", "rm", "mkdir"],
    "correctIndex": 0
  },
{
    "subject": "Linux",
    "question": "Which command is used to list files in a directory?",
    "options": ["list", "ls", "dirlist", "show"],
    "correctIndex": 1
  },
  {
    "subject": "Linux",
    "question": "What does the 'pwd' command do?",
    "options": ["Prints working directory", "Permanently wipe data", "Protects files", "Pauses system"],
    "correctIndex": 0
  },
  {
    "subject": "Linux",
    "question": "Which command is used to change file permissions?",
    "options": ["chperm", "chmod", "chown", "permset"],
    "correctIndex": 1
  },
  {
    "subject": "Linux",
    "question": "What symbol represents the home directory?",
    "options": ["/", "~", ".", ".."],
    "correctIndex": 1
  },
  {
    "subject": "Linux",
    "question": "Which command is used to search for text within files?",
    "options": ["search", "find", "grep", "scan"],
    "correctIndex": 2
  },
  {
    "subject": "Docker",
    "question": "Which command is used to build a Docker image from a Dockerfile?",
    "options": ["docker run", "docker build", "docker image", "docker compose"],
    "correctIndex": 1
  },
 {
    "subject": "Docker",
    "question": "Which instruction in a Dockerfile sets the base image?",
    "options": ["CMD", "FROM", "ENTRYPOINT", "BASE"],
    "correctIndex": 1
  },
  {
    "subject": "Docker",
    "question": "Which Dockerfile instruction is used to set an environment variable?",
    "options": ["ENV", "VAR", "SET", "EXPOSE"],
    "correctIndex": 0
  },
  {
    "subject": "Docker",
    "question": "Which flag is used with 'docker run' to mount a volume?",
    "options": ["--net", "-m", "-v", "--bind"],
    "correctIndex": 2
  }
]



